A Guide to the Margaret Freeman Cabell Papers 1910-1982
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
Margaret Freeman Cabell Papers, 1910-1982
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 228
19 linear feet and oversize material
Margaret Freeman Cabell
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated to the Department by Mrs. Cabell in her will.
Biographical/Historical Information
Margaret Waller Freeman Cabell (1894-1983), an interior decorator and a supporter of the arts in Richmond, Virginia, was the second wife of writer James Branch Cabell (1879-1958). Born in Richmond in 1894, her family lived for a brief time on the 100 block of North Linden Street directly across the street from what would some 70 years later the James Branch Cabell Library at Virginia Commonwealth University.
She was a graduate of Miss Jennie Ellett's School (now St. Catherine's School). In the 1920s she was one of four founding editors of the Richmond based literary magazine the Reviewer where she served mainly as its business manager. She later received training as a nurse and during World War II she helped head the Stage Door Canteen in Washington, D.C. She then went on to operate her own interior-decorating studio in New York City (she had studied interior design briefly in Paris in the 1920s). It was during this time she worked under the name Waller Freeman.
James Branch Cabell, at the suggestion of his son Ballard, began courting Margaret Freeman in 1949, soon after his first wife died.
"The idea of becoming Mrs. James Branch Cabell appealed to Margaret Freeman," wrote Edgar MacDonald in his biography of Cabell published in 1993. "As the wife of a once-famous writer, her niche in history would be assured; for her remaining years she could reign as a social leader in a Richmond that had patronized her."
Margaret married James Branch Cabell in 1950 and did go on to become a cultural presence in Richmond, principally in support of the arts. An example of her involvement in Richmond was her active role in raising funds to restore the late-19th century built Confederate Chapel located behind what is now the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts. She was a member of the Woman's Club of Richmond, the United Daughters of the Confederacy, and the Colonial Dames of America. She was also active in advancing the literary legacy of her husband. She co-edited a volume of Cabell's letters published in 1962 entitled Between Friends: Letters of James Branch Cabell and Others; founded the James Branch Cabell Society; and throughout the 1960s and 1970s she encouraged scholars and academics to write about husband, who had died in 1958. In the late 1960s she agreed to donate his personal library of 3,000 volumes and his remaining literary papers to the Academic Campus library of the newly formed Virginia Commonwealth University (during the 1950s and 1960s, many of his papers were donated to the University of Virginia's Alderman Library). Thanks mainly to her support of VCU and its new library, built 1970-1975, the building was named for James Branch Cabell. Her social connections in Richmond helped bring in other donations of books and manuscript collections which formed the founding core of the library's newly formed Special Collections and Archives department.
Her relationship with Cabell's only offspring, Ballard Hartwell Cabell (1915-1980), was strong and her encouragement of him to pursue art led to several exhibitions in Richmond of his paintings. Ballard died in 1980. Margaret died March 28, 1983.
Scope and Content Information
The Collection consists of the papers, memorabilia, photographs, scrapbooks and miscellania of James Branch Cabell, Margaret Waller Freeman Cabell, Ballard Hartwell Cabell, John Brightwell Freeman and John Middleton Freeman. The majority of the collection is composed of correspondence between Mr. Cabell and his friends. There is some cross-over of correspondence between individuals who were clients of Mrs. Cabell's (Waller Freeman) interior design business who later became friends and individuals who were friends of the Cabell's but also corresponded as representatives of organizations or companies. In such instances, the letter has been placed in the series most closely corresponding to the intent and content of the correspondence and cross references are listed when known.
Arrangement
Arrangement
All series are arranged topically, alphabetically and chronologically therein, excluding oversize and photographic items which are housed separately from the collection.
Organization
Series I-- Personal Correspondence [includes letters to James Branch Cabell and both Mrs. Cabells] (n.d., 1866-1978)
Series II--Miscellaneous (n.d., 1950-1975)
Series III--Personal Material (n.d., 1948- 1953)
Series IV--Organizational Correspondence (n.d., 1923-1977)
Series V--World War I Correspondence [MWF] (n.d., 1917-1927)
Series VI--Plays and Creative Writings (n.d., 1920-33)
Series VII-- Margaret Waller Freeman Correpondence (with sub-series Client Correspondence and Confederate Chapel Correspondence) (n.d., 1931-1973)
Series VIII--John Brightwell Freeman Papers (n.d., 1930-1968)
Series XI--John Middleton Freeman Papers (n.d.)
Series X--Miscellaneous and Oversize Materials (n.d.)
Series XI--Artifacts (n.d.)
Series XII--Publications and Miscellaneous Printed Matter.
Contents List
- Series I--Personal Correspondence, n.d. 1866-1978
  - Abbott, Dolly 1957 (Box 1)
  - Acherton, Gertrude 1921 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Helen 1957 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Randolph 1948 (Box 1)
  - Aldrich, Wiley B. 1964 (Box 1)
  - Allan, Eve 1959 (Box 1)
  - Allen, Edward Frank 1956 (Box 1)
  - Allsopp, Sydney 1972 (Box 1)
  - Almond, J. Lindsay, Jr. (Attorney General) 1954 (Box 1)
  - Alsop, Ellie, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Alsop, Em Bowles (W. Wilson Centennial Celebration Comm.) 1956-1957 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Martin (Orlando Morning Sentinel) 1942 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Alfred S. 1933 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Philip Ashby, Sr. 1952 (Box 1)
  - Archer, Edmund Minor, n.d. 1959-1963 (Box 1)
  - Arons, Peter L. 1960 (Box 1)
  - Arthur, Chester A., Jr. 1933 (Box 1)
  - Artinian, Artine 1938 (Box 1)
  - Austen, Carl, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Ayer, Leta and Thomas P. 1938 (Box 1)
  - Babb, James T., n.d. (Box 1)
  - Bailey, R.E. 1944 (Box 1)
  - Bakeless, John 1950 (Box 1)
  - Baker, Grace Grant 1930 (Box 1)
  - Ballard, Virginia S. 1957 (Box 1)
  - Ballew, Hal 1941 (Box 1)
  - Bancroft, Caroline, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Barba, Martha 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Barber, Jackson 1938 (Box 1)
  - Barlow, R.H. 1933-1934 (Box 1)
  - Barlow, Samuel, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Barr, Ingle 1960 (Box 1)
  - Barrett, Waller and Cornelia, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Baskette, Ewing C. 1958 (Box 1)
  - Baskin, Norton 1949-1973 (Box 1)
  - Bates, E.S. 1933 (Box 1)
  - Baugh, Hansell, n.d. 1929 (Box 1)
  - Beckelhymer, Paul Hunter 1956 (Box 1)
  - Beddoe, Frank 1939 (Box 1)
  - Beer, Alice 1959-1975 (Box 1)
  - Beer, Thomas photos, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Bela, Nicholas 1942 (Box 1)
  - Bell, Dick 1967 (Box 1)
  - Bell, Thomas 1930 (Box 1)
  - Bellamy, John E. (dissertation Reputation of J.B.Cabell) 1954 (Box 1)
  - Benda, Lilith 1922 (Box 1)
  - Benet, Laura 1943 (Box 1)
  - Benet, Rosemary (Mrs. Stephen Vincent) 1956 (Box 1)
  - Benet, William Rose, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Bennett, Anne Virginia 1940-1953 (Box 1)
  - Benoliel, D. Jacques 1952 (Box 1)
  - Berman, Solomon M., n.d. (Box 1)
  - Bernaert, Edouard (Compagnie Francaise d'Edition) 1922 (Box 1)
  - Bernhard, John Wlliam 1930 (Box 1)
  - Bettman, Otto L. (Bettman Archives) 1955 (Box 1)
  - Bhat, K.S. 1930 (Box 2)
  - Biekell, Herschel (NY Evening Post) 1934 (Box 2)
  - Bingham, Mary Caperton (Mrs. Barry) 1970 (Box 2)
  - Bjorkman, Edwin 1923-1951 (Box 2)
  - Blackford, James Baylor 1970 (Box 2)
  - Blackwell, James E. 1973 (Box 2)
  - Blair, Julie 1940 (Box 2)
  - Blanton, Natalie (Mrs. Wyndham) 1956 (Box 2)
  - Blish, James (Kalki) 1970-1974 (Box 2)
  - Bond, Nelson (listed under publishers) (Box 2)
  - Bonner, G. 1932 (Box 2)
  - Booth, William Harris, n.d. 1954 (Box 2)
  - Bowie, L. 1942-1945 (Box 2)
  - Bowie, Walter Russell 1950-1969 (Box 2)
  - Bowles, Elizabeth Hawes 1955 (Box 2)
  - Boyd, Julian P. 1942-1959 (Box 2)
  - Boyd, Madeline 1959 (Box 2)
  - Boyd, Richard E., Jr. 1967-1976 (Box 2)
  - Bradshaw, Herbert 1975 (Box 2)
  - Branch, Anna Hempstead (see Ethel Legman) (Box 2)
  - Branch, C.H. Hardin 1974 (Box 2)
  - Branch, James R. 1866-1869 (Box 2)
  - Branch, James Ransom, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Branch, Sarah Gayle, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Branch, Thomas 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Brander, Elizabeth 1957 (Box 2)
  - Brewer, George and Frances 1956-1969 (Box 2)
  - Brewster, Paul G. 1941 (Box 2)
  - Bright, J. Fumer (Mayor) 1937 (Box 2)
  - Brinkman, Julia Wiggins 1948 (Box 2)
  - Brock, Para Lee (WGPC Radio) 1936 (Box 2)
  - Bround, H. Datnall 1935-1936 (Box 2)
  - Brown, E. Allan, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Brown, Robert B. 1939-1951 (Box 2)
  - Brucoli, Matthew 1957 (Box 2)
  - Brussel, I.R. (Sesphra Library Service) 1928-1967 (Box 2)
  - Bryan, David Tennant 1956 (Box 2)
  - Bryan, Joseph III, n.d. 1929 (Box 2)
  - Bryan, Thomas P. 1958 (Box 2)
  - Bryant, Arthur H. 1949 (Box 2)
  - Buck, Nina, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Burkholder, John A., n.d. 1951 (Box 2)
  - Burnett, Hallie 1946 (Box 2)
  - Burnett, Whit 1942-1947 (Box 2)
  - Burton, Richard, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Burwell, Mary 1946 (Box 2)
  - Bush, Chatmon 1931-1944 (Box 2)
  - Butcher, Fanny (Chicago Tribune), n.d. 1933 (Box 2)
  - Buttitta, A.J. (Contempo) 1933 (Box 2)
  - Buxton, Aline A., n.d. (Box 2)
  - Byrd, Harry Flood (U.S. Senator) 1953 (Box 2)
  - Byrd, Harry F. Jr. 1969 (Box 2)
  - Cabell, Anna 1943 (Box 3)
  - Cabell, Ballard H., n.d. 1955-1956 (Box 3)
  - Cabell, Elizabeth 1972 (Box 3)
  - Cabell, John, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Cabell, John, L., n.d. 1935-1943 (Box 3)
  - Cabell, Landon 1971 (Box 3)
  - Cabell, Mariana Foster 1957 (Box 3)
  - Cabell, Mark Harriss, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Cabell, Priscilla 1972-1976 (Box 3)
  - Cabell, Randolph (Cabell Memorial Association) 1955 (Box 3)
  - Cabell, Robert Gamble III 1911-1958 (Box 3)
  - Cabell, Robert Gamble III, n.d. 1957-1959 (Box 3)
  - Cabell, Robert Gamble IV 1949-1957 (Box 3)
  - Cabell, Robert Gamble V 1956 (Box 3)
  - Cabell, Royal E., Jr., n.d. 1970, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Cabell, Royal E., Jr. 1965-1970 (Box 3)
  - Caldwell, Erskine, n.d. 1943 (Box 3)
  - Calvo, Doucie (?), n.d. (Box 3)
  - Campbell, Jack (University of Florida) 1948 (Box 3)
  - Cane, Melville H. 1961 (Box 3)
  - Cannan, Gilbert 1919 (Box 3)
  - Caperton, Helena L. 1931-1962 (Box 3)
  - Caperton, Helena L., n.d. 1956, 1975 (Box 3)
    including clippings
  - Carpenter, Margaret (Virginia Authors Yearbook) 1957 (Box 3)
  - Carrington, Mary Coles, n.d. 1948 (Box 3)
  - Carson, Bobby and Jeanne, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Carter, Lin 1954-1969 (Box 3)
  - Casanova, Grace Hegger (Mrs. Telesforo) 1953-1969 (Box 3)
  - Cash, W.T. (Florida State Library Board) 1942-1943 (Box 3)
  - Chamberlain Mable 1949 (Box 3)
  - Chandler, Marion 1975 (Box 3)
  - Chapman, Katherine Townsend, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Chase, Harold B. 1946 (Box 3)
  - Chatterji, N. 1957 (Box 3)
  - Cheslock, Louis 1929-1931 (Box 3)
  - Chidsey, Donald Barr 1928 (Box 3)
  - Childs, Marquis W. (St. Louis Post-Dispatch) 1931 (Box 3)
  - Christian, Evelyn, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Chubb, Thomas Caldecot 1930-1936 (Box 3)
  - Clairborne, Virginia 1974 (Box 3)
  - Clark, Adele, n.d. 1932 (Box 3)
  - Clark, Adele, n.d. 1975 (Box 3)
    with newspaper clippings
  - Clark, Edward, T., n.d. 1952-1963 (Box 3)
  - Clark, Emily (Mrs. E.S. Balch) 1930-1953 (Box 3)
  - Claytor, Gertrude, n.d. 1972, 1974-1976 (Box 3)
  - Clemens, Cyril (Int'l Mark Twain Society) 1933 (Box 3)
  - Clemens, Samuel (Box 3)
  - Clough, Ruth Crary 1947 (Box 3)
  - Coates, Christopher W. 1962-1971 (Box 3)
  - Cockrell, Edison (Mr. and Mrs.) 1971-1973 (Box 3)
  - Cohnan, Morris 1926 (Box 3)
  - Coleman, Mary Virginia Holmes 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Collins, Marjorie, n.d. 1963 (Box 3)
  - Collins, Roslyn 1944 (Box 3)
  - Colum, Padraic 1961 (Box 3)
  - Colum, Padraic, clippings 1957-1960, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Conger, Dorothea Tatum 1956-1961 (Box 3)
  - Conger, Edwin 1968-1974 (Box 3)
  - Congereve, Marjorie 1971 (Box 3)
  - Cook, Nellie Davenport, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Cook, Minnie G. 1934 (Box 3)
  - Cooke, Philip 1956 (Box 3)
  - Cooley,Franklin D. 1967 (Box 3)
  - Coombs, Elizabeth M. 1957 (Box 3)
  - Corley, Donald 1931 (Box 3)
  - Coudenhove, Countess 1951 (Box 3)
  - Cournos, John 1920 (Box 3)
  - Cover, James P. 1928-1929 (Box 3)
  - Cowles, Dudley R. 1951 (Box 3)
  - Cranwell, John Phillips (Baltimore Sun) 1929-1932 (Box 3)
  - Crittenden, Ethel Stuart, n.d. 1966 (Box 4)
  - Croft-Cooke, Rupert, n.d. 1928 (Box 4)
  - Crowley, Aleister, n.d. 1919-1923 (Box 4)
  - Crown, James E. 1937 (Box 4)
  - Crute, A.M. 1951-1952 (Box 4)
  - Culver, Henry B. 1943-1944 (Box 4)
  - Cunningham, Col. Harry Francis 1932 (Box 4)
  - Curle, Richard 1930 (Box 4)
  - Cutler, Esther B. 1972 (Box 4)
  - Cutler, Ronald 1957 (Box 4)
  - D'Isere, Guy 1922 (Box 4)
  - Dabney, Virginius 1932 (Box 4)
  - Dallet, Morris, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Damon, S. Foster (Brown University Library), n.d. 1930-1931 (Box 4)
  - Daniel Frank, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Daniel, Richard P. 1942 (Box 4)
  - Darden, Colgate (UVA Office of President) 1957 (Box 4)
  - Darden, Colgate W., Jr. (JBCL Associates) 1971 (Box 4)
  - Davidson, Robin 1968 (Box 4)
  - Davis 1955 (Box 4)
  - Davis, Curtis Carroll 1949-1966 (Box 4)
  - Davis, Joe Lee (see also Twayne Publishers, Inc.) 1951-1970 (Box 4)
  - Davis, Priscilla, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Davis, Virginia 1955 (Box 4)
  - De Casseres, Benjamin 1919, 1924 (Box 4)
    (copies of two letters from JBC, 1919, 1924, from Bond Collection
  - De Casseres, Benjamin, n.d. 1926-1938 (Box 4)
  - De Casseres, Benjamin (from De Casseres to Frederic Eddy) 1924 (Box 4)
  - de Guzman, Daniel, n.d. 1933 (Box 4)
  - de la Ree, Gerry 1974 (Box 4)
  - De Luca, Angelo, n.d. (Box 4)
  - de Navarro, Philip 1933 (Box 4)
  - de Roussy de Sales, Raoul 1922 (Box 4)
  - Del Mar, Ronald H. 1939-19740 (Box 4)
  - Dean, Nina Oliver 1942 (Box 4)
  - Debasil, Col. W. 1937 (Box 4)
  - Decker, Florence B., n.d. (Box 4)
  - Deford, Louise McAdams 1955 (Box 4)
  - DeHeck, Charles 1971 (Box 4)
  - Denvil, Jane 1954-1957 (Box 4)
  - Derieux, Sam 1975 (Box 4)
  - Disque, Brice, Jr. 1934-1947 (Box 4)
  - Dodge, Gregory D. 1974 (Box 4)
  - Dodge, Wendell Phillips, Jr. 1935 (Box 4)
  - Dolmetsch, Carl R. 1955 (Box 4)
  - Donahoe, Mickey, n.d. 1970 (Box 4)
  - Doughton, Richard, n.d. 1932 (Box 4)
  - Douglass, Jane 1963 (Box 4)
  - Drake, Leah Bodine, n.d. 1939 (Box 4)
  - Drummond, Andrew H. 1974 (Box 4)
  - Drummond, Andrew H. 1976 (Box 4)
  - du Pont, Jessie Ball 1942 (Box 4)
  - Duke, Jane Taylor 1956 (Box 4)
  - Duke, Maurice, n.d. 1968-1975 (Box 4)
  - Dunn, Mary Catherine, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Durham, Frank 1961 (Box 4)
  - Duschnes, Philip C. 1938 (Box 4)
  - Eaton, Evelyn 1952 (Box 4)
  - Edmunds, Abe Craddock (The Little Bookshop) 1932-1933 (Box 4)
  - Edmunds, Murrell 1930-1949 (Box 4)
  - Edwards, Ward (Central MO State Teacher's College), n.d. (Box 4)
  - Eggli, Eric M. 1962-1966 (Box 4)
  - Eich, John W., n.d. 1946-1963 (Box 4)
  - Eichler, David K. 1934 (Box 4)
  - Elgstrom, Anna L. 1930 (Box 4)
  - Emmons, E.H. 1935-1947 (Box 4)
  - Emory, Emma Gray 1970 (Box 5)
  - Engle, Hilda P. 1940 (Box 5)
  - Englewood, Margaret B., n.d. (Box 5)
  - Ernst, Morris L. 1968 (Box 5)
  - Eshleman, Lloyd 1939 (Box 5)
  - Eskridge, Ralph 1956-1962 (Box 5)
  - Ethier, Thomas 1926 (Box 5)
  - Evans, Jean, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Evans, Montgomery, II n.d. 1929-1948 (Box 5)
  - Fadiman, Clifton 1957 (Box 5)
  - Farsaci, Larry B. 1955 (Box 5)
  - Feldman, Robert A. 1956 (Box 5)
  - Fenimore, Agnes Branch 1942 (Box 5)
  - Fenton, Charles 1954 (Box 5)
  - Fessenden, Reginald A., n.d. (Box 5)
  - Field, Jane (Mrs. Kenneth C.) 1964 (Box 5)
  - Fielden, Gordon 1971 (Box 5)
  - Fielder, Leslie, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Fischer, Walter 1962 (Box 5)
  - Fishburne, Junius R., Jr. 1960 (Box 5)
  - Fisher, Mahlon L., n.d. 1927 (Box 5)
  - Fisher, Vardis 1952 (Box 5)
  - Fishwick, Marshall W. 1947-1957 (Box 5)
  - Fisk, Earl E. 1946 (Box 5)
  - Flinn, F. Wayne 1933 (Box 5)
  - Flora, Joseph M. 1970 (Box 5)
  - Follett, Wilson 1920-1959 (Box 5)
  - Forest, G. Christopher 1958 (Box 5)
  - Forester, Norman 1932 (Box 5)
  - Forgue, Guy Jean 1958-1959 (Box 5)
  - Forsyth, Elizabeth, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Fox, Lawrence W. 1964 (Box 5)
  - Frank, Glenn 1921 (Box 5)
  - Frank, Waldo 1920 (Box 5)
  - Freeman, Charles, n.d. 1950-1952 (Box 5)
  - Freeman, Charles, n.d. 1960s-1970s (Box 5)
  - Freeman, Margaret Waller, n.d. 1949-1950 (Box 5)
  - Freeman, Douglas Southall 1952-1953 (Box 5)
  - Freeman, Inez G. 1971 (Box 5)
  - Freeman, John Brightwell 1961-1969 (Box 5)
  - Freeman, John Middleton, n.d. 1958-1975 (Box 5)
  - Freeman, John Middleton 1966-1969 (Box 5)
  - Friedman, Philip Allan 1952-1953 (Box 5)
  - Fuller, Nel 1974 (Box 5)
  - Gage, George 1934 (Box 6)
  - Galantiere, Lewis 1922-1923 (Box 6)
  - Gale, Ima, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Gallagher, Marie, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Gardner, B. n.d. (Box 6)
  - Gardner, Mary Carter Anderson 1943 (Box 6)
  - Gardner, May, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Garland, Mary L. 1957 (Box 6)
  - Gates, Arnold F. 1941-1965 (Box 6)
  - Gay, William T. 1965 (Box 6)
  - Gay(le), William 1933-1937 (Box 6)
  - Geismar, Maxwell 1953-1954 (Box 6)
  - Gekle, William F., Jr., n.d. 1940-1941 (Box 6)
  - Giacomini, Lynwood 1961-1963 (Box 6)
  - Gibson, Churchill J., Rev. n.d. (Box 6)
  - Gibson, Irene, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Gimmestad, Victor E. 1975 (Box 6)
  - Gingrich, Arnold 1957 (Box 6)
  - Giorgi, Rose 1965 (Box 6)
  - Glaenzer, Jules 1965 (Box 6)
  - Glasgow, Archie R. 1958 (Box 6)
  - Glasgow, Arthur Graham 1947-1955 (Box 6)
  - Glasgow, Ellen, n.d. 1927-1958 (Box 6)
  - Glasgow, Margaret 1947 (Box 6)
  - Glenn, Garrard 1932 (Box 6)
  - Glenn, Isa 1931 (Box 6)
  - Godbold, E. Stanly, Jr. 1968-1972 (Box 6)
  - Goddin, Alfred P. 1961 (Box 6)
  - Godshalk, William Leigh (Kalki) 1967-1974 (Box 6)
  - Goldhurst, William 1962 (Box 6)
  - Goldsmith, Alfred F., n.d. 1933-1947 (Box 6)
  - Goldstone, Adrian 1959-1963 (Box 6)
  - Goodman, J. Stuart 1939 (Box 6)
  - Gore, Luther Y. 1967 (Box 6)
  - Graves, L.W., n.d. (Box 6)
  - Gray, William S. 1969 (Box 6)
  - Grebanier, Bernard 1965-1975 (Box 6)
  - Greenway, Cornelius, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Gregory, Edward Meeks, Rev. 1971 (Box 6)
  - Gresham, Hattie Bell, n.d. 1931 (Box 6)
  - Griffith, Priscilla (Mrs. Dalton A. and daughter of Emmet Shephard) 1958 (Box 6)
  - Guerard, Albert, Sr., n.d. 1935-1949 (Box 6)
  - Hall, James N. 1966-1967 (Box 6)
  - Hall, Raymond Carlisle, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Halling, Martin A., n.d. 1937 (Box 6)
  - Hamblin, Basil 1967 (Box 6)
  - Hamilton, Clayton (The Players) 1932 (Box 6)
  - Hamilton, Sinclair 1969-1973 (Box 6)
  - Hanna, Alfred J., n.d. 1938-1942 (Box 7)
  - Hanna, Alfred J. 1943-1975 (Box 7)
  - Hanna, Kathryn Abbey, n.d. (Box 7)
  - Hanren, Harry 1933 (Box 7)
  - Hanson, Endicott 1942 (Box 7)
  - Hapgood, Elisabeth 1956-1969 (Box 7)
  - Harding, T. Swann 1934 (Box 7)
  - Harris, Jean 1975 (Box 7)
  - Harrison, W.M. 1943 (Box 7)
  - Hart-Davis, Rupert 1950-1959 (Box 7)
  - Hartman, Harry 1963-1970 (Box 7)
  - Hartman, Sadakichi 1944 (Box 7)
  - Hathaway, Henry S. 1963-1964 (Box 7)
  - Hawkins, Nina 1955 (Box 7)
  - Head, John Thomas 1955 (Box 7)
  - Head, Thomas 1977 (Box 7)
  - Hellman, George S. 1924 (Box 7)
  - Hellman, Lillian 1974 (Box 7)
  - Henderson, Archibald 1947 (Box 7)
  - Henneman, Bill 1940 (Box 7)
  - Hensley, Donald M. 1965 (Box 7)
  - Hergesheimer, Dorothy, n.d. 1959-1964 (Box 7)
  - Herndon, Brodie S. 1966 (Box 7)
  - Hervey, Harry, n.d. 1941-1950 (Box 7)
  - Hill, Evelyn 1974 (Box 7)
  - Hillman, Marguerite Wright, n.d. 1972 (Box 7)
  - Himelick, Raymond, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Hinricks, Paul (the Play Masters), n.d. (Box 8)
  - Hobson, Fred C., Jr. 1970-1972 (Box 8)
  - Hoffa, Helen 1943-1944 (Box 8)
  - Holt, Guy (Robert M. McBride and Co.) 1925-1934 (Box 8)
  - Holt, Hamilton (Rollins College) 1940-1941 (Box 8)
  - Holt, Rackham 1936-1962 (Box 8)
  - Hiiker, Edward Niles, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Horan, Tom Y., n.d. 1950-1970 (Box 8)
  - Horch, Franz J., n.d. 1947 (Box 8)
  - Horner, Henrietta 1950 (Box 8)
  - Hornickel, Laura Kerr Rivkin, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Hoskins, William Barnes 1950-1953 (Box 8)
  - Howard, John Melville 1936-1937 (Box 8)
  - Howard, Thomas W. 1971 (Box 8)
  - Houghland, Willard Heiderlander 1932 (Box 8)
  - Hoyt, Helen 1919 (Box 8)
  - Hundall, William Leon 1970 (Box 8)
  - Hewbsch, George V. 1939 (Box 8)
  - Hull, Maude Pollard 1956 (Box 8)
  - Hummel, Ray 1976 (Box 8)
  - Hunter, Marie D. 1949 (Box 8)
  - Hutchings, Emily Grant 1937 (Box 8)
  - Irwin, Inez H. 1949 (Box 8)
  - Irwin, William Wallace 1947 (Box 8)
  - Jackson, Alan (Paramount Pictures) 1946 (Box 8)
  - Jamerson, Osmond T. 1971 (Box 8)
  - Jenkins, Jim Jr. 1948-1976 (Box 8)
  - Jennings, Anne 1969 (Box 8)
  - Johns, Frank Stoddart, Dr., n.d. (Box 8)
  - Johnson, Jean L. 1964 (Box 8)
  - Johnson, Martha Granville, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Johnson, Merle, n.d. 1931 (Box 8)
  - Johnson, William R. 1958 (Box 8)
  - Johnston, Frances 1936 (Box 8)
  - Johnston, J. Amber 1971 (Box 8)
  - Jones, Daniel 1973 (Box 8)
  - Jones, Edward C. 1961 (Box 8)
  - Jones, Violet 1960 (Box 8)
  - Kandel, Alen, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Kane, Harnett T. 1960-1961 (Box 8)
  - Kastor, Robert 1935 (Box 8)
  - Kay, C. Robert 1935 (Box 8)
  - Keating, George T. 1932-1935 (Box 8)
  - Keepers, Emma, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Kelley, Leon 1929-1932 (Box 8)
  - Kellner, Bruce 1967 (Box 8)
  - Kemler, Edgar 1949 (Box 8)
  - Kendrick, Baynard 1946-1961 (Box 8)
  - Kennedy, Leo 1944 (Box 8)
  - Kenney, R.A. 1951 (Box 8)
  - Kerrigan, Marjorie Burke 1950-1951 (Box 9)
  - Kessler, Charles L. 1965 (Box 9)
  - Kester, Katharine 1951 (Box 9)
  - King, Louisa (Alfred A. Knopf) 1943 (Box 9)
  - Klinefelter, Walter 1936-1937 (Box 9)
  - Kling, Samuel G. 1946 (Box 9)
  - Kluge, Emile 1968 (Box 9)
  - Knight, R.F. 1952 (Box 9)
  - Koch, Peter 1928 (Box 9)
  - Kramer, Maurice and Elaine S.F. (Brooklyn College) 1968 (Box 9)
  - L'Engle, Lucy 1967 (Box 9)
  - Langford, Gerald (University of Texas) 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Lagner, Lawrence 1951-1962 (Box 9)
  - Lanier, Henry (the Players) 1932 (Box 9)
  - Larrson, Katherine S. 1947 (Box 9)
  - Lassagne, Theodore Hawley 1937-1938 (Box 9)
  - LaTouche, John Treville (see also Andrew H. Drummond) 1932-1940 (Box 9)
  - LaTouche Photographs (Box 9)
  - Lavender, T.E., n.d. (Box 9)
  - Lawson, E.W. 1946-1949 (Box 9)
  - Layton, L. Lee, Jr. 1972-1977 (Box 9)
  - Leacock, Stephen 1923 (Box 9)
  - Lee, Lawrence 1929 (Box 9)
  - Lee, Stuart S. 1961 (Box 9)
  - Lee, W. Storrs 1970 (Box 9)
  - Legman, Ethel (Anna Hempstead Branch) 1939 (Box 9)
  - LeGrand, Peggy 1947-1955 (Box 9)
  - LeMarechal, Jacques 1942 (Box 9)
  - Lengel, William C. 1934 (Box 9)
  - Lennon, Thomas Lloyd 1931 (Box 9)
  - Lerner, Daniel, n.d. (Box 9)
  - Levai, Blaise 1947 (Box 9)
  - Lewis, Sinclair 1943-1958 (Box 9)
  - Lewis, Walter B. 1933 (Box 9)
  - Lipsey, Julia F. 1933 (Box 9)
  - Littleton, Anne 1963 (Box 9)
  - Lockridge, Norman 1936 (Box 9)
  - Loomis, Battell, n.d. (Box 9)
  - Lottier, Mary P. 1964 (Box 9)
  - Loverman, Samuel 1931 (Box 9)
  - Loving, Boyce 1935 (Box 9)
  - Lublin, Alfred W. 1932 (Box 9)
  - Lutz, Mark 1967 (Box 9)
  - Lyon, John H. 1936 (Box 9)
  - Mabbott, Maureen 1971 (Box 9)
  - Mabbott, Thomas 1954 (Box 9)
  - MacDonald, Edgar E. 1955 (Box 9)
  - MacDonald, Rose 1944 (Box 9)
  - Machen, Arthur 1959 (Box 9)
  - Mack, Ted, n.d. 1937 (Box 9)
  - Macy, John 1926-1955 (Box 9)
  - Magill, Frank 1959-1965 (Box 9)
  - Malcolmson, David 1941 (Box 9)